{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "A Mass-Spring-Damper system having force as input and displacement of the mass as output having transfer function:G(s)=1/(s^(2 )+24s+900)  . A force input F (t) =10 sin (70t) is applied at time t=0 s. A beam from an optical stroboscope is focused on the mass .In steady-state the strobe frequency in hertz at which the mass appears to be stationary is,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "5/&#960;",
        "b": "35/&#960;",
        "c": "15/&#960;",
        "d": "50/&#960;"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "An accelerometer has input range of 0 to 10 g. Natural frequency 30 Hz and mass of 0.001 kg. The range of secondary displacement transducer required to cover the input range is,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0 to 2.76",
        "b": "0 to 9.81",
        "c": "0 to 11.20",
        "d": "0 to 52.10"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The equation of free vibration of a system is   (d^2 x)/〖dt〗^2 +64π^2 x=0, its natural frequency would be,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "4 π Hz",
        "b": "4 Hz",
        "c": "8 π Hz",
        "d": "64 π^2 Hz"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The equation of motion of a spring mass damper system is    (d^2 x)/〖dt〗^2 +3dx/dt+9kx=10 sin⁡(5t). The damping factor for the system is,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.25",
        "b": "2",
        "c": "0.5",
        "d": "3"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The equation of motion of a spring mass damper system is    (d^2 x)/〖dt〗^2 +3dx/dt+9kx=10 sin⁡(5t). The damping factor for the system is,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.25",
        "b": "2",
        "c": "0.5",
        "d": "3"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "A vehicle suspension system consists of a spring and damper. The stiffness of the spring is 3.6 kN/m and the damping constant of the damper is 400 Ns/m. If the mass value is 50 kg, then the value of damping factor &#950; and damped natural frequency (fd) are,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.471,1.19 Hz",
        "b": "0.666,1.35 Hz",
        "c": "0.471,7.48 Hz",
        "d": " 0.666,8.50 Hz"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Two bodies of different mass m1 and m2 are dropped from heights of h1 and h2 respectively,neglecting the effect of friction the ratio of times taken to drop them from the given heights is,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "(h1/h2)^1/2",
        "b": "m1/m2 Hz",
        "c": "m1h1/m2h2",
        "d": " h1/h2"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In an oscillating mass-spring system, the velocity of the mass is greatest when the mass is,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "at the equilibrium point",
        "b": "at the point of maximum displacement",
        "c": "at the point where acceleration is greatest.",
        "d": "halfway between the equilibrium point and maximum displacement"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "An object attached to an ideal spring executes simple harmonic motion. If you want to double its total energy, you could",
      "answers": {
        "a": "double the force constant (spring constant) of the spring",
        "b": "double the amplitude of vibration",
        "c": "double both the amplitude and force constant (spring constant). ",
        "d": "double the mass"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "A mass 'm' is attached to a light spring oscillates with a period of 2 seconds.If the mass is increased by 2 kgs,the period is increased by 1 seconds.The value of mass is,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1.6kg",
        "b": "2.1kg",
        "c": "0.9kg",
        "d": "2.7kg"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "A vibrating system consists of a mass of 200kg and a spring stiffness of 80N/mm,the natural frequency of vibration of the system is,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "20 rad/s",
        "b": "40 rad/s",
        "c": "5.0 rad/s",
        "d": "2.5 rad/s"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "A block whose mass is 4kg, is fastened to a spring of spring constant 64 N/m. The block is pulled from its equilibrium position in a frictionless surface and released,the period of resulting motion in seconds is,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "&#960;/2",
        "b": "&#960;/4",
        "c": "2&#960;",
        "d": "4&#960;"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "A particle attached to a vertical spring and pulled down to 0.01m below its mean position and released,its initial acceleration is 0.16m/s^2,the time period in seconds will be,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "&#960;/2",
        "b": "&#960;/4",
        "c": "2&#960;",
        "d": "4&#960;"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen correct answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen wrong answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Stretching a spring increases its ______________ energy",
      "answers": {
        "a": "gravitational potential",
        "b": "mechanical kinetic",
        "c": "vibrational kinetic",
        "d": "elastic potential"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Frequency of a spring is 'n' after suspending mass 'M'. Now after suspending mass '4M' the frequency wil be,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2n",
        "b": "n/4",
        "c": "n",
        "d": "n/2"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The period of oscillation of a mass 'M' suspended from a spring of negligible mass is T,if along with it another mass M is also suspended,the period of oscillation will now be",
      "answers": {
        "a": "T",
        "b": "T/6",
        "c": "T/&#8730;2",
        "d": "&#8730;2 T"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "b": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "c": "You have chosen wrong answer",
        "d": "You have chosen correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }













  ]
}
